To be part of a team of hi-caliber professionals for challenging assignments and responsibilities as DevOps engineer with 1.5+ years of experience thus sharpening my own professional skills and at the same time contributing my best to the overall development of the organization.

Professional Experience

Zimbra Technology, Technical Solutions Engineer

10/2021 - present | Pune, India

- Fix Zimbra mail server related issues in large and heterogeneous environments, handle Escalations.
- Supporting 5000+ customers on zimbra which is an open source full featured collaboration.
- Implemented CI/CD pipeline for zimbra application using jenkins and reduced manual effort by 80%.
- Maintaining 100% of zimbra scripts on Github and regularly working with the teams through version control.
- Analysing the critical scenarios and identifying bugs and reporting in JIRA in a day to day basis.
- Streamlined AWS VM and service creation with Terraform reduced provisioning time by 60% and ensuring accurate infrastructure setup.
- Implemented configuration management tools like Ansible to automate the deployment of code changes.
- Designed and maintained the company's CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins with GITHub ensuring that code changes are automatically deployed to aws vm.

DXC Technology

Linux/Unix Deep Support – L3

05/2021 - 10/2021 | Indore, India

- Incident management: Breakthrough fix, escalation, and major incidents calls.
- Cluster support Service guard & Symantec Veritas.
- VMWare & HP Blade server Support & troubleshooting like VM resource management which includes add/remove CPU,RAM and disks sizes, VM Migrations from S2S & Cluster to cluster, RCA for problem management tasks. VM Creation and deletion.
- Monitoring servers health with ansible playbooks and shell scripts.

Linux/Unix and Windows - Infra-L2

01/2019 - 04/2021 | Indore, India

- Client support for Windows & Linux platform within defined SLA.
- Backup support on HP data protector tool within defined SLA.
- Provide support on ticket management tool (HPSM, Service Now) in SLA timeline.
- Provide support like server down, cluster package or service down on windows, Linux, Unix, VMware server.

AlphaInfolab Pvt. Ltd., Linux System Engineer

05/2017 - 12/2018 | Indore, India

- Linux talent:- essential skills in handling files, working at the command line, along with managing systems, boot-up, identifying processes, configuring storage partitions and logical volumes, automating maintenance tasks with shell scripts and working with services like Apache, NFS, MariaDB, PowerDNS,BIND, SMTP(postfix, sendmail Dovecot), link Aggregation and security services like FirewallD, SElinux, configuring bulk Email Server using PowerMTA.
- Monitoring and managing servers using Zabbix.
- Deploy VM on KVM Hypervisior and proxmox.

Projects

Coming soon.....

- Deployed a container orchestration for node.js to-do list app using Kubernetes and Docker.
- Add one more line

Coming Soon.....

- Deployed a container orchestration for node.js to-do list app using Kubernetes and Docker.
- Add one more line

ADITYA PATIDAR

Technical Solutions Engineer

adpatidar.patil@gmail.com

+91-9713977237

Indore (Madhya Pradesh)

https://github.com/adpatidar

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adityapatidar-1bb609b8

Skills

- Docker
- Jenkins
- Kubernetes
- AWS
- Ansible
- Terraform
- Git and Github
- Linux/Unix
- Shell Scripting

Certificates

RHCE (Global Certification: (EX300) Red Hat Certified Engineer)

Awards

DXC Collaborators award,

DXC Technology

DXC Champs award, DXC Technology

Education

Bachelor of Engineering,

Rajiv Gandhi Tehnical University Bhopal, India

Languages

English Hindi

